Guide to the Consumer Reports. Colston E. Warne papers, 1910-1995 and undated RL.11784
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, Speeches, Testimonies, 1922-1982 and undated; 9
  - Speeches, Talks, Lectures, 1929-1979 and undated; 9
    - 197. The Consumer Movement Meets McCarthyism, CEW Lecture Series, Kansas State University, 1977 (Box 119)
    - 198. New Directions in Consumerism: 1953-1966-, CEW Lecture Series, Kansas State University, 1977 (Box 119)
    - 199. New Initiatives on the International Consumer Front, CEW Lecture Series, Kansas State University, 1977 (Box 119)
    - 200. The Nader Network, CEW Lecture Series, Kansas State University, 1977 (Box 119)
    - 201. Wither Consumerism?, CEW Lecture Series, Kansas State Univ., 1977 (Box 119)
    - 202. The Roots of Consumerism, Fifth Annual Seminar for Directors of Consumer Agencies and State and Local Government, 1977 (Box 119)
    - 203. Welcome to Helen Nelson, Consumers Union, 1977 (Box 119)
    - 204. Address to CU Staff, Consumers Union, 1978 (Box 119)
    - 205. Consumer Protection, A Survey of Institutional Arrangements and Legal Measures, International Organization of Consumers Unions, 1978 (Box 119)
    - 206. Untitled, American Council on Consumer Interests, 1979 (Box 119)
    - 207. A Consumer Assessment of the Supermarket Era, undated (Box 119)
    - 208. Consumer Education for America Labor, undated (Box 119)
    - 209. The Consumer Function and Conditions for Its Competent Performance, undated (Box 119)
    - 210. Consumer Protection in America, undated (Box 119)
    - 211. Consumerism, undated (Box 119)
    - 212. Government Intervention in American Labor Disputes, undated (Box 119)
    - 213. The Impact of Consumer Testing Agencies on Consumer Expenditures, undated (Box 119)
    - 214. The International Consumerism of Our Day, undated (Box 119)
    - 215. The Permanent Values in Civilization, undated (Box 119)
    - 216. The Role of the Consumer Today, undated (Box 119)
    - 217. Too Much and Too Poor, undated (Box 119)
    - 218. Washington Forum, undated (Box 119)
    - 219. Washington speech, undated (Box 119)
    - 220. What Can the Consumer Movement Do American Society?, undated (Box 119)
    - 221. The World of Advertising, undated (Box 119)
    - 222. Untitled, undated (Box 119)
    - 223. Untitled, undated (Box 119)
    - 224. Untitled, undated (Box 119)
    - 225. Untitled, undated (Box 119)
  - Statements and Testimonies, 1943-1971 and undated; 10
    - 1. Statement before the Senate Committee on Agriculture, 1943 (Box 119)
    - 2. Testimony, 1943 (Box 119)
    - 3. Statement before the Banking and Currency Committee, 1945 (Box 119)
    - 4. Statement in the Matter of Arbitration of the Philadelphia Company and the Independent Association of Employers of the Duquesne Light Company, 1946 (Box 119)
    - 5. Statement for the Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, 1947 (Box 119)
    - 6. Statement on the Proposed Charter for an International Trade Organization, Boston, Mass., 1947 (Box 119)
    - 7. Statement on the "Loyalty Oath", 1947 (Box 119)
    - 8. Statement submitted to the Joint Committee on the Economic Report, 1947 (Box 119)
    - 9. Testimony before the Senate Foreign Affairs Committee on the North Atlantic Pact, 1949 (Box 119)
    - 10. Statement to the Round Table Discussion held by the Joint Committee on the Economic Report of the President, 1950 (Box 119)
    - 11. Statement on Economy, Trade, and Foreign Policy, 1950 (Box 119)
    - 12. Statement on Rent Control to the Sub-Committee on Housing and Rents, 1950 (Box 119)
    - 13. Statement, "An Answer to Charges Against Consumers Union", 1951 (Box 119)
    - 14. Testimony For Res. 169, 1952 (Box 119)
    - 15. Statement to the Jenner Committee, 1953 (Box 119)
    - 16. Statement to the Jenner Committee, 1953 (Box 119)
    - 17. Statement before the Sub-Committee on Anti-Trust and Monopoly of the Committee on the Judiciary of the United States Senate, Hearing on S. 215 (Price Notification Bill), 1959 (Box 119)
    - 18. Statement at the Federal Trade Commission Conference on Deception, 1959 (Box 119)
    - 19. Statement on Hearings on Packaging and Labeling Practices before the Sub-Committee on Anti-Trust and Monopoly, of the United States Senate Committee on the Judiciary, 1961 (Box 119)
    - 20. Testimony on Senate Res. 1552, 1961 (Box 119)
    - 21. Statement at the Federal Bar Association Annual Conference before a panel on the subject: "Is further legislation needed in the field of food, drugs, and cosmetics to protect the consumer?", 1965 (Box 119)
    - 22. Testimony before the Executive and Legislative Reorganization Sub-Committee of the House Committee on Government Operations, 1966 (Box 119)
    - 23. Testimony to the Sub-Committee on Consumer Interests of the Elderly, United States Senate Special Committee on Aging, on Hearing Loss, Hearing Aids, and the Older American, 1968 (Box 119)
    - 24. Testimony at Hearings on Trade Regulation Rules Regarding Games of Chance in the Food Retailing and Gasoline Industries, 1969 (Box 119)
    - 25. Statement on the Food Shortage, 1970 (Box 119)
    - 26. Testimony at the Hearings on the New York State Fair Trade Law, 1971 (Box 119)
    - 27. Testimony at the Hearings of the Sub-Committee on Commerce and Finance of the United States House of Representatives Cornrnittee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, on Automobile Insurance Reform, 1971 (Box 119)
    - 28. Testimony on Automobile Insurance, 1971 (Box 119)
    - 29. Statement to the House Banking and Currency Committee, Hearings on Wage-Price Freeze, 1971 (Box 119)
    - 30. Statement of the Association of Food and Drug Officials of the United States, undated (Box 119)
    - 31. Statement on Japanese Automobile Insurance, undated (Box 119)
  - Other Writings: For Consumers Union, 1937-1978 and undated; 11
    - 1. A Survey of Consumers Unxon of United States, 1937 (Box 119)
    - 2. A Study of Policy Trends in Consumers Union, 1947 (Box 119)
    - 3. Consumers Union After Fifteen Years, 1951 (Box 119)
    - 4. On CU, 1953 (Box 119)
    - 5. Consumers Union: A Report on Its Educational Activities, 1955 (Box 119)
    - 6. Report on Speaking Tour, 1955 (Box 119)
    - 7. Statement of Operating Rules for Relations Between Director, Treasurer, and Controller of Consumers Union, 1957 (Box 119)
    - 8. International Consumer Organization Formed in The Hague April 1, 1960 (Box 119)
    - 9. Draft of Speech on CU given at Amherst College, 1961 (Box 119)
    - 10. International Office of Consumers Unions, 1961 (Box 119)
    - 11. Consumers Union's Thirtieth Anniversary, 1961 (Box 119)
    - 12. Preliminary Proposal for Local Organization of CU Members, 1962 (Box 119)
    - 13. Report on European Trip, 1963 (Box 119)
    - 14. Report on Local British Groups, 1967 (Box 119)
    - 15. Notes on Ways to Set Up a Consumers Union, undated (Box 119)
    - 16. Report on Trip to Europe, 1969 (Box 120)
    - 17. Report on Trip: Summary of Consumer Situation in Countries of the Pacific Area, 969 (Box 120)
    - 18. Report on Trip to Mid-West Universities, 1971 (Box 120)
    - 10. Brief History of Consumers Union Of U.S., 1971 (Box 120)
    - 20. Highlights of Trip to Asia, 1971 (Box 120)
    - 21. Comments on Sorensen Report, 1972 (Box 120)
    - 22. Comment concerning interview with Frank Palmer, 1973 (Box 120)
    - 23. Comment on Morton Mintz Article, 1973 (Box 120)
    - 24. Response to Nash Ditlow Report, 1973 (Box 120)
    - 25. Introduction to the program of the discussion groups of the Working Seminar for South East Asia and the Pacific, 1974 (Box 120)
    - 26. Consumers Union's Fortieth Anniversary, 1976 (Box 120)
    - 27. Irving Michelson & Florence Mason, 1978 (Box 120)
    - 28. Consumer Agencies, undated (Box 120)
    - 29. The Consumer Movement After the Year 2000, undated (Box 120)
    - 30. Consumers Union - It Works!, undated (Box 120)
    - 31. Early Chapter in the Evolution of CU's Board Structure, undated (Box 120)
    - 32. Food presentation, undated (Box 120)
  - Other Writings: General, 1922-1979 and undated; 12
    - 1. A Study of the Bonus System, The Chicago Bridge and Iron Works, 1922 (Box 120)
    - 2. Conditions in the Mining Camps, 1927 (Box 120)
    - 3. The Human Cost of Coal, 1928 (Box 120)
    - 4. The XYZ Mining Company, A Case Study in Industrial Warfare, 1928 (Box 120)
    - 5. A Jaunt Through the Mining Camps of Central Pennsylvania, 1928 (Box 120)
    - 6. Industrial Conditions in Pittsburgh, 1930 (Box 120)
    - 7. Business Analysis, 1931 (Box 120)
    - 8. Henry Wallace, 1933 (Box 120)
    - 9. Industrial Structure in a Socialist Society, 1933 (Box 120)
    - 10. The Consumer's Stake, 1934 (Box 120)
    - 11. Total Capital Flotations: Domestic and Foreign, 1934 (Box 120)
    - 12. Planning in Russia, 1934 (Box 120)
    - 13. Work Service Camps in Germany, 1934 (Box 120)
    - 14. The Growth of the American Consumer Movement, 1937 (Box 120)
    - 15. Background on Paper Milk Containers, 1938 (Box 120)
    - 16. Comments on Consumer Financed Testing and Rating Agencies in the United States, 1938 (Box 120)
    - 17. Protecting the Consumer, 1938 (Box 120)
    - 18. The Consumers' Counsel of the Agricultural Adjustment Administration, 1938 (Box 120)
    - 19. Science and the Consumer Movement, 1939 (Box 120)
    - 20. Report on a Consumer Broadcasting Station, 1940 (Box 120)
    - 21. Academic Freedom, 1940 (Box 120)
    - 22. Private Companies Use Tax Money for Self-Glorification and Inflation, 1940 (Box 120)
    - 23. Advertising Waste and the Newspaper Industry, 1943 (Box 120)
    - 24. Pupil Participation in Consumer Education, 1943 (Box 120)
    - 25. Price Control, 1945 (Box 120)
    - 26. Paper Shortage, 1945 (Box 120)
    - 27. Employment, 1946 (Box 120)
    - 28. Random Impressions of Warsaw, 1947 (Box 120)
    - 29. An Impression of Europe, 1948 (Box 120)
    - 30. Report on Anti-Inflation Conference, 1951 (Box 120)
    - 31. On Advertising, 1952 (Box 120)
    - 32. On Mechanization, 1952 (Box 120)
    - 33. Lincoln Clark, 1954 (Box 120)
    - 34. Wise Buymanship, 1956 (Box 120)
    - 35. Middlebury, 1958 (Box 120)
    - 36. Consumer Representation in Government, 1960 (Box 120)
    - 37. Who Should Educate Young Consumers?, 1960 (Box 120)
    - 38. The Movement for Consumer Representation in State Governments, 1960 (Box 120)
    - 39. Consumer Protection and Representation in Government, 1960 (Box 120)
    - 40. The Aftermath of the Election, 1960 (Box 120)
    - 41. Protecting the Consumer (Interview), 1960 (Box 120)
    - 42. Prospects and Problems of Consumers, 1961 (Box 120)
    - 43. An Assessment of Consumer Protective Efforts in Israel, Pakistan, India, Japan, Australia, and New Zealand, 1962 (Box 120)
    - 44. Does the Organized Consumer Handicap Economic Expansion?, 1962 (Box 120)
    - 45. The International Development of Consumer Organizations, 1962 (Box 120)
    - 46. Health Protection, 1969 (Box 120)
    - 47. The International Organization of Consumers Unions, 1969 (Box 120)
    - 48. International Consumer Movement in the 1970s, 1971 (Box 120)
    - 49. Consumerism and the Future, 1971 (Box 120)
    - 50. Robert L. Smith, 1971 (Box 120)
    - 51. Conference with Richard Nixon, 1971 (Box 120)
    - 52. Working Seminar for South-East Asia and the Pacific, 1974 (Box 120)
    - 53. Ralph Nader, 1975 (Box 120)
    - 54. Comment on Memorandum by H.R. Arthur - Council of Economic Advisers, 1979 (Box 120)
    - 55. Analyzing the American Market - A Maze For Buyers, undated (Box 120)
    - 56. The Consumer, Victim of Unorganized Business, undated (Box 120)
    - 57. Consumers Lose a Friend, undated (Box 120)
    - 58. Fair Trade, undated (Box 120)
    - 59. Glimpse at the Consumer Advice Center of Havering, England, undated (Box 120)
    - 60. On Cooperative Planning, undated (Box 120)
    - 61. A Summary of Interviews in the USSR, undated (Box 120)
    - 62. A Summary of the Rhode Island Plan of Local Price Panel Participation in Price Control, undated (Box 120)
    - 63. Proposed Objectives for the American Consumer Movement, undated (Box 120)
    - 64. The Trade Unionists and Consumer Economics, undated (Box 120)
    - 65. On Galbraith, undated (Box 120)
    - 66. On Government, undated (Box 120)
    - 67. On Leland Gordon, undated (Box 120)
    - 68. On the Market Place, undated (Box 120)
    - 69. On Price Control, undated (Box 120)
    - 70. On Price Maintenance, undated (Box 120)
  - Other Writings: Numbers 3-11, 1925-1982; 13
    - 3. The Consumers' Cooperative Movement in Illinois, (Doctoral dissertation, University of Chicago), 1925 (Box 121)
    - 4. Why Consumer Education?, chapter for a Consumer Education Book, 1942 (Box 121)
    - 5. The UAW and the Sit-Down Strikes, undated (Box 121)
    - 6. Report on Activities and Associations, 1930-1953 (Box 121)
    - 7. A Cursory Survey of European Consumer Movements, 1959 (Box 121)
    - 8. Consumer Protective Movements on the State and Local Levels, 1963 (Box 121)
    - 9. Consumer Protective Movements on the State and Local Levels, 1964 (Box 121)
    - 10. Contacts in South America, 1969 (Box 121)
    - 11. Consumers Union's Contribution to the Consumer Movement, Part II, Chapter 5, "Consumer Activists, They Made a Difference", 1982 (Box 121)
    - Clipping file, 1929-1979 and undated; 4 folders (Box 122)
- Personal Materials, 1910-1987 and undated; 10
  - Family, 1925-1980 and undated; 14
    - Corbett, 1940-1959 (Box 123)
    - Estey, 1928-1933 (Box 123)
    - McLaughlin, undated (Box 123)
    - Nelson, Margaret Warne, 1944-1966 (Box 123)
    - Nelson, Paul Jr., 1947-1968 (Box 123)
    - Nelson, Paul, 1954-1958 (Box 123)
    - Newell, Barbara Warne, 1948-1980 (Box 123)
    - Tower, Celia Warne, 1926-1967 (Box 123)
    - Tower, Ralph, 1926-1956 (Box 123)
    - Warne, Clinton A., 1925-1954 (Box 123)
    - Warne, Clinton L., 1937-1968 (Box 123)
    - Warne, Clyde, 1926-1958 (Box 123)
    - Warne, Frances, 1925-1974 (Box 123)
    - Warne, Harriet, 1932 and undated (Box 123)
    - Estate of Clinton A. Warne, 1955-1959; 4 folders (Box 123)
    - Genealogies, family histories, undated (Box 123)
      Includes The Warne Genealogy, Walking on Water (Celia Warne Tower)
  - Other Material, 1910-1987 and undated; 15
    - Oldest known letter by Colston Warne, 1910 (Box 124)
    - Ithaca High School year book, 1916 (Box 124)
    - Ithaca High School reunion, 1966 (Box 124)
    - Cornell University, approximately 1920; 2 folders (Box 124)
      Includes Student handbook, Class of 1920 directory, reunion material, grade reports, etc.
    - Resumes, undated (Box 124)
    - Financial records, 1927-1952 and undated (Box 124)
      Includes Henry Richards tax material, Teachers Insurance, etc.
    - Honors and awards, 1977-1980 (Box 124)
      Includes American Marketing Association; Honorary degree, Bowie State College; Amherst College; others
    - Students working in the consumer field, 1972-1979 (Box 124)
    - Colston Warne obituary, memorial service, tributes, etc., 1987; 3 folders (Box 124)
  - Scrapbooks, 1916-1979; 16
    - Ithaca High School, 1916-1967 (Box 125)
      Includes student scrapbook, 50th reunion materials
    - Photograph album, 1966-1978 and undated (Box 127)
    - Photograph album--Trip to India, 1969 (Box 128)
    - "Greetings to Colston E. Warne"--Retirement from Amherst College, 1969 (Box 126)
    - Seventy-fifth Birthday, 1975 (Box 127)
    - Retirement from Consumers Union, 1979; 6 folders (Box 127)
      Includes correspondence, guest lists, programs, speakers
    - Retirement from Consumers Union--Memory book, 1979 (Box 128)
- Additions, 1932-1995 and undated; 11
  - Asia trip, 1962 (Box 129)
  - Awards, 1959-1972 (Box 129)
  - Awards--Bowie State College Honorary Doctor of Economics, 1977 (Box 129)
  - Awards--Greece, 1979 (Box 129)
  - Awards--Massachusets, 1979 (Box 134)
  - Biographical information, 1979 and undated (Box 129)
  - Board of Directors--Term of service of Board members, 1973 (Box 129)
  - Caricature, 1935 (Box 129)
  - Certificate of Incorporation--National Association of Consumers, 1955 (Box 134)
  - Clinton Warne (father), 1952-1955; 2 folders (Box 129)
  - Clinton Warne (father), 1952-1954 (Box 131)
  - Clinton Warne (father)--Ledger sheets, 1940-1943 (Box 134)
  - Clippings, 1948-1988; 2 folders (Box 129)
  - Clippings, 1932-1995 (Box 134)
  - Clippings--Communism, 1935 (Box 134)
  - Clippings--Germany, 1933 (Box 134)
  - Clippings--Japan, 1962, 1987 (Box 134)
  - Colston Warne Fellowship, 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 129)
  - Colston Warne Fellowship, 1980-1982 (Box 131)
  - Colston Warne Program, 1981-1997 (Box 129)
  - Conference--Consumer Problems in a Period of International Tensions, 1952 (Box 129)
  - Conflict of Interest Committee--Jean Morris/Scott Maynes case, 1974 (Box 129)
  - Consumer Interest Research Institute--Proposal, 1981 (Box 129)
  - Consumer Union (CU) history, 1970-1979 (Box 129)
  - Consumer Union ledger--Expenses and membership, 1948-1951 (Box 133)
  - Consumer Union ledger--Membership register, 1947-1950 (Box 133)
  - Consumer Union ledger sheets, 1948-1956 (Box 134)
  - Copyright/royalties, 1971-1980 (Box 129)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1986 (Box 129)
  - Death--Condolences, 1987; 2 folders (Box 129)
  - Death--Estate, 1987-1989 (Box 129)
  - Death--Memorial service, 1987 (Box 129)
  - Death--Obitusaries, 1987; 2 folders (Box 129)
  - Events at the University of Pittsburgh (Academic freedom issue), 1935 (Box 129)
  - Japan trip, 1962; 2 folders (Box 129)
  - Japan trip--Calligraphy, 1962 (Box 131)
  - Lecture posters, 1955 and undated (Box 134)
  - Miscellaneous, 1939-2002; 2 folders (Box 129)
  - Oral history project (Consumers Union), 1979-1982 (Box 129)
  - Pacific trip, 1972-1974 (Box 129)
  - Photographs, 1950-1981 and undated (Box 129)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 134)
  - Photographs--Album (removed from album), 1962-1977 and undated (Box 129)
  - Public Affairs Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 129)
  - Retirement dinner, 1979 (Box 129)
  - Retirement tribute album from COTACO (Comite de trabajadores para ayudar al consumidor, Puerto Rico), 1979 (Box 132)
  - Retirement tribute album from friends and associates, 1979 (Box 132)
  - Sketch by Richard Baratz, 1979 (Box 134)
  - Subversive charges--Loyalty check, 1947 (Box 131)
  - Subversive charges--Report on Activities and Associations 1930-1953 (Box 129)
  - Tribute dinner program design, undated (Box 129)
  - Tributes, 1969-1997; 2 folders (Box 129)
  - Consumer Education: Its New Look (Bulletin of the National Association of Secondary School Principals), 1967 (Box 130)
  - Consumers' Protection and Interest Program (John F. Kennedy), 1962 (Box 130)
  - Consumers Union: Methods, Implications, Weaknesses and Strengths (Ruby Turner Morris), 1971 (Box 130)
  - Global Trade in Dangerous Products (IOCU) press kit, 1983 (Box 131)
  - Informationally Imperfect Consumer Markets (E. Scott Maynes, Terje Assum), 1982 (Box 130)
  - New Masses newsletter, 1935 (Box 131)
  - Prestel in Use (E. Scott Maynes), 1982 (Box 130)
  - A Rebel's Odyssey, 1941 (Box 130)
  - Consumers Union After Fifteen Years, 1951 (Box 130)
  - Event announcements, 1957 and undated (Box 130)
  - Miscellaneous, 1941-1950 and undated (Box 130)
  - Speech binder, 1961 (Box 130)
  - The Consumer Movement manuscript (Warne lectures edited by Richard Morse), 1992 (Box 130)
  - The Steel Strike of 1919 manuscript, undated (Box 130)